<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on My Wiki</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/</link><description>Recent content in Home on My Wiki</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ayushnix.com/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Does DNS Work?</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/networking/how-does-dns-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 20:37:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/networking/how-does-dns-work/</guid><description>Introduction # Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did for hosting my website on GitHub Pages using a custom domain. I&amp;rsquo;ll think about self hosting using a web server on a VPS later.
Go ahead and purchase a domain from a registrar which offers decent purchase as well as renewal prices on domains. Choose a top-level domain (TLD) which doesn&amp;rsquo;t restrict WHOIS privacy and has DNSSEC. The .com TLD fulfills these criteria but the .</description></item><item><title>Shell Scripting</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/shell/scripting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:02:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/shell/scripting/</guid><description>Introduction # Knowing how to use your shell and being able to write scripts that work across different Unix-like operating systems can be an incredibly important skill. I&amp;rsquo;ve often thought about it as an essential skill that a sysadmin should possess. However, there are various complications when it comes to using shell scripts.
although bash is the most popular shell out there, it isn&amp;rsquo;t the standard shell used across all Unix-like systems</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Git</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/devops/git/getting-started-with-git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 20:41:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/devops/git/getting-started-with-git/</guid><description>Instead of rote learning and hoping not to mess up when executing git commands, it&amp;rsquo;s better to understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on under the hood and how git actually works. This guide isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be a traditional git 101 guide. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover basic terminology briefly but focus solely on git internals because, in my opinion, that&amp;rsquo;s how one should get started with git.
Introduction # There are several insightful one line definitions of what a git repository is but we&amp;rsquo;ll start with this one.</description></item><item><title>Linux Desktop Is a Shit Show</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/rants/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:01:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/rants/linux/</guid><description>Doing The Unusual — Criticising Linux # These are the collection of my gripes and frustrations I&amp;rsquo;m either facing right now, or have faced in the past, when using the Linux, or GNU/Linux if you will, on the desktop. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux on my desktop exclusively since 2015 instead of Windows 10 or MacOS.
For people out there who&amp;rsquo;re pedantic and radicalized enough to miss the point of the article, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just about the Linux kernel itself but about using Linux ecosystem on a desktop.</description></item><item><title>tmux</title><link>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/tools/tmux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 22:23:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://ayushnix.com/wiki/docs/sysadmin/tools/tmux/</guid><description>Basics # To find out the default value of an option, use the command
$ tmux show -g &amp;lt;option&amp;gt; Attach and Detach # You can specify session names using
$ tmux new -s first You can attach to that particular session later using
$ tmux attach -t first To create a new session,
$ tmux new -d -P -s 1 or simply use :new from the tmux status line.</description></item></channel></rss>